Mary Leighton Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- A Recollection of Ireland in December 1860., Leighton, Frances Christina, d. 1930; 1 volume (15 drawings; 1 photograph); 11.5 x 24.5 cm. Contemporary morocco binding with gilt-ruled border. (Box Vol. 10)
  Unlike the other volumes in the collection, this sketchbook was created to document a specific event. Inscribed "A Recollection of Ireland / in December 1860 / To Charlotte Leighton, / form her affecate sister F.," the sketchbook includes watercolors that document the siblings' trip to Ireland. It begins with an image of Thornhill—likely the home of the Leightons' Irish hosts—and includes tourist sites featuring both natural and architectural wonders. Judging from the order of the drawings, the travelers appear to have begun their tour in County Monaghan in the north and traveled as far south as County Wicklow. The final image in the sketchbook is a group photograph of the traveling party, whose members are identified by annotations on the facing page.
  Ireland; Watercolors; Leighton, Frances Christina, d. 1930; Leighton, Charlotte, d. 1928; Thornhill family